<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Comparing the Effects of Hypothetical Moral Preferences on Real-Life and Hypothetical Behavior: Commentary on Bostyn, Sevenhant, and Roets (2018)</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
							<email>a.m.evans@uvt.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Social Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tilburg University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 90153</postBox>
									<postCode>5000 LE</postCode>
									<settlement>Tilburg</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Social Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tilburg University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brandt</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Social Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tilburg University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Comparing the Effects of Hypothetical Moral Preferences on Real-Life and Hypothetical Behavior: Commentary on Bostyn, Sevenhant, and Roets (2018)</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">0008545A29E64F40C928B5F0C39E7F18</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797618815482</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received 5/23/18; Revision accepted 10/25/18</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-06T16:29+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>consequentialism</term>
					<term>morality</term>
					<term>trolley</term>
					<term>utilitarianism</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ASSOCIATION FOR PSYCHOLOGICAL SCIENCE</head><p>Commentary Do hypothetical preferences predict real-life moral behavior? <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bostyn, Sevenhant, and Roets (2018)</ref> conclude that there are notable discrepancies between the psychological processes underlying decisions in real-life and in hypothetical moral dilemmas, adding to recent critiques of the moral-dilemma empirical paradigm <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bauman, McGraw, Bartels, &amp; Warren, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Kahane, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kahane et al., 2018)</ref>. One of their central findings is that hypothetical preferences for consequentialism were significantly correlated with consequentialist behavior when participants responded to a hypothetical dilemma (odds ratio, or OR = 2.14, z = 2.17, p = .030) but not when a separate sample of participants was presented with a real-life version of the same dilemma (OR = 1.35, z = 0.83, p = .406). Their study raises important questions about whether experiments based on hypothetical scenarios, such as trolley-style dilemmas, can be used to understand the processes underlying real-life moral behavior.</p><p>Our Commentary addresses a limitation of the analyses of Bostyn and colleagues: Namely, they did not directly compare the effects of consequentialist-reasoning preferences on hypothetical and real-life moral behavior. In other words, their analyses tested whether consequentialist-reasoning preferences were associated with behavior within each sample, but they did not test whether these two effects were significantly different from each other. The strategy of focusing only on within-group analyses and interpreting significance dichotomously can lead to erroneous conclusions (such as Type II errors) and the misinterpretation of significant results (e.g., a main effect may be interpreted as an interaction effect; <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Gelman &amp; Stern, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Nieuwenhuis, Forstmann, &amp; Wagenmakers, 2011)</ref>. To address this limitation, we conducted new analyses that tested the interaction between consequentialist-reasoning preferences and dilemma type (real-life vs. hypothetical).</p><p>In our new analyses, we combined the data from the two samples collected by Bostyn and colleagues (i.e., the real-life dilemma and the hypothetical dilemma) and then reestimated the logistic regression model used to predict consequentialist behavior (i.e., the willingness to shock one mouse in order to save five). Importantly, our new model also included an indicator of dilemma type and dilemma-type-by-reasoning-preferences interaction terms.</p><p>The results are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Replicating the authors' analyses, our tests showed a significant main effect of dilemma type; participants were more likely to make a consequentialist decision in the real-life condition than in the hypothetical condition, p = .03. There was also a main effect of consequentialist preferences; participants with consequentialist preferences were more willing to make consequentialist choices, p = .03. Critically, there were no significant interactions between experimental condition and moral-reasoning preferences, ps &gt; .32.</p><p>To get a sense of the evidence for or against the presence of an interaction, we followed the approach of Bostyn and colleagues: We used Bayesian analyses to examine the nonsignificant interaction between dilemma type and consequentialist preferences. We estimated the Bayes factor using the Savage-Dickey density ratio <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Wagenmakers, Lodewyckx, Kuriyal, &amp; Grasman, 2010)</ref> in the brms package <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bürkner, 2016)</ref> in the R programming environment, using a weakly informative Student's t distribution (ν = 3, µ = 0, s = 2.5) as a prior. This analysis yielded a Bayes factor of 3.47, moderate evidence for the hypothesis that there was no interaction between dilemma type and preferences for consequentialist reasoning.</p><p>There are at least two interpretations of these new results: One interpretation is that the original study lacked sufficient power to detect an interaction effect. Indeed, the study had 46% power to detect a mediumsized effect (OR = 2 or Cohen's d = 0.30). This view suggests that there are insufficient data to confirm (or disconfirm) the presence of an interaction. Alternatively, we can take the Bayes factor at face value and draw a preliminary conclusion based on the evidence at hand: The present results provide moderate evidence for the hypothesis that moral-reasoning preferences have similar effects for real and hypothetical decisions, though further studies are needed to strengthen (or weaken) this conclusion. Both interpretations call for additional studies; however, the second gives us informed expectations going forward.</p><p>Our new analyses are consistent with a large body of interdisciplinary research suggesting that hypothetical preferences correspond, albeit imperfectly, with real-life behavior. For example, a meta-analysis of 82 studies by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Balliet, Parks, and Joireman (2009)</ref> found that social value orientation, a hypothetical measure of altruistic preferences, reliably predicted behavior in both real-life and hypothetical social dilemmas. Similarly, studies on individual risk taking <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kühberger, Schulte-Mecklenbeck, &amp; Perner, 2002)</ref> and intertemporal choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bickel et al., 2010)</ref> suggest that the processes underlying hypothetical and real-life financial decisions are similar. At the same time, this evidence does not mean that moral psychology should rely on hypothetical dilemmas as the stimuli of choice. The key question is whether such dilemmas are able to capture the relevant psychological processes underlying the moral situations that people actually face in real life (it is not clear that they do; <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bauman et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>In sum, there is insufficient evidence to support the conclusion that hypothetical preferences have different effects for real-life and hypothetical dilemmas. Despite this result, there are differences between behavior in real-life and hypothetical dilemmas. Indeed, several studies, including this one, point to the conclusion that mean levels of behavior differ in real and hypothetical dilemmas <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bostyn et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">FeldmanHall, Mobbs, et al., 2012)</ref>; participants are more willing to be utilitarian when the consequences are real. Moreover, real and hypothetical decisions sometimes involve different neural regions and cognitive processes <ref type="bibr">(FeldmanHall, Dalgleish, et al., 2012)</ref>. 1 Surely, much can be learned when psychologists go beyond hypothetical self-reports to observe real-life behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Baumeister, Vohs, &amp; Funder, 2007)</ref>. However, we cannot clearly conclude whether moralreasoning preferences have differing effects for real-life and hypothetical dilemmas.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Action Editor</head><p>D. Stephen Lindsay served as action editor for this article.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Declaration of Conflicting Interests</head><p>The author(s) declared that there were no conflicts of interest with respect to the authorship or the publication of this article.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Funding</head><p>The writing of this Commentary was supported with funding from the European Research Council under the European Union's Horizon 2020 research and innovation program (Grant No. 759320).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Note</head><p>1. Several individual-differences variables were unrelated to behavior in the real-life dilemma; however, these variables </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Effects of Dilemma Type (Real-Life vs. Hypothetical) and Moral-Reasoning Preferences on Behavior</figDesc><table><row><cell>Predictor</cell></row></table><note><p>Note: OR = odds ratio.</p></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Evans, Brandt</head><p>were not included in the hypothetical-dilemma sample. Thus, we cannot conclude how they differ between the two samples.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social value orientation and cooperation in social dilemmas: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Balliet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Parks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Joireman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Group Processes &amp; Intergroup Relations</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="533" to="547" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting external validity: Concerns about trolley problems and other sacrificial dilemmas in moral psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bauman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mcgraw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bartels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Warren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social &amp; Personality Psychology Compass</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="536" to="554" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychology as the science of self-reports and finger movements: Whatever happened to actual behavior?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baumeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Vohs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Funder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="403" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hypothetical intertemporal choice and real economic behavior: Delay discounting predicts voucher redemptions during contingency-management procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Bickel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Landes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mancino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="546" to="552" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Of mice, men, and trolleys: Hypothetical judgment versus real-life behavior in trolley-style moral dilemmas</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bostyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sevenhant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Roets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797617752640</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1084" to="1093" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">brms: An R package for Bayesian multilevel models using Stan</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P.-C</forename><surname>Bürkner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18637/jss.v080.i01</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differential neural circuitry and self-interest in real vs hypothetical moral decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Feldmanhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Dalgleish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schweizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mobbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="743" to="751" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What we say and what we do: The relationship between real and hypothetical moral choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Feldmanhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mobbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hiscox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Navrady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Dalgleish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2012.02.001</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The difference between &quot;significant&quot; and &quot;not significant&quot; is not itself statistically significant</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Statistician</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="328" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sidetracked by trolleys: Why sacrificial moral dilemmas tell us little (or nothing) about utilitarian judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kahane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="560" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond sacrificial harm: A two dimensional model of utilitarian decisionmaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kahane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A C</forename><surname>Everett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Earp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Caviola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Faber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Savulescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="164" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Framing decisions: Hypothetical and real</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kühberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schulte-Mecklenbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Perner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1162" to="1175" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Erroneous analyses of interactions in neuroscience: A problem of significance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nieuwenhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Forstmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1105" to="1107" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian hypothesis testing for psychologists: A tutorial on the Savage-Dickey method</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lodewyckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kuriyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Grasman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="158" to="189" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
