<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Wearing a Bicycle Helmet Can Increase Risk Taking and Sensation Seeking in Adults</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Gamble</surname></persName>
							<email>t.gamble@bath.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>BA2 7AY</postCode>
									<settlement>Bath</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Wearing a Bicycle Helmet Can Increase Risk Taking and Sensation Seeking in Adults</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">A49E3A9949525B0845572439BED92820</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797615620784pss.</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received 9/8/15; Revision accepted 11/12/15</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.2" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-03T10:35+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<label type="revision">a91ee48</label>
					<label type="parameters">startPage=-1, endPage=-1, consolidateCitations=0, consolidateHeader=0, consolidateFunders=0, includeRawAffiliations=false, includeRawCitations=false, includeRawCopyrights=false, generateTeiIds=false, generateTeiCoordinates=[], sentenceSegmentation=false, flavor=null</label>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>SSXXX10.1177/0956797615620784Gamble</term>
					<term>WalkerHelmets</term>
					<term>Risk Taking</term>
					<term>and Sensation Seeking risk taking</term>
					<term>sensation seeking</term>
					<term>social priming</term>
					<term>bicycling</term>
					<term>protective equipment</term>
					<term>behavior change</term>
					<term>open data</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>People's perceptions of safety influence their risk taking. This phenomenon, studied under such rubrics as risk compensation <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Adams &amp; Hillman, 2001)</ref>, risk homeostasis <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Wilde, 1998)</ref>, and risk allostasis <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Lewis-Evans &amp; Rothengatter, 2009)</ref>, is typified by people taking increased risks when using protective equipment <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Adams, 1982)</ref> or at least reducing their risk taking when protective equipment is absent <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Fyhri &amp; Phillips, 2013;</ref> Phillips, Fyhri</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>in which the helmet could do nothing to change risk. We also measured sensation seeking and anxiety as possible explanatory variables for any effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Eighty participants (15 male and 24 female in the helmet condition, 19 male and 22 female in the cap condition) between the ages of 17 and 56 years (M = 25.26, SD = 6.59) took part in the study; no monetary reward was offered for participation. An a priori power analysis showed that 40 participants per condition should have 80% power to detect an effect size (Cohen's d) of 0.63. This was deemed sufficient, as we hoped to see relatively substantial effects of the helmet manipulation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>State anxiety was measured using the State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI) Form Y-1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Spielberger, 1983)</ref>. This form contains 40 questions, 20 that measure a person's feelings of anxiety right at the moment of response and 20 that measure his or her chronic levels of anxiety. Participants here answered the former set. In the BART <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Lejuez et al., 2002)</ref>, which we programmed in Real Studio <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Xojo, 2011)</ref>, participants pressed a button to inflate an animated balloon on a computer screen. Each button press inflated the balloon more and increased the amount of fictional currency earned. If the balloon burst (which it would at a random point between 1 and 128 inflations), all earnings for that trial were lost. At any point, participants could choose to stop pumping and "bank" their accrued money. After the balloon burst, or after a decision to bank, the next trial began. Each participant completed 30 trials, and his or her risk-taking score was the mean number of pumps made on trials on which the balloon did not burst. This score would be higher when participants risked losses by trying to maximize their score and lower when participants avoided risk and played more conservatively.</p><p>Sensation seeking was measured using the Sensation-Seeking Scale Form V <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Zuckerman, Eysenck, &amp; Eysenck, 1978)</ref>. This scale measures four dimensions (10 selfreport items each) of sensation-seeking behavior: thrill and adventure seeking, disinhibition, experience seeking, and boredom susceptibility. Bicycling frequency was measured using a Likert scale ranging from 1 (never) to 6 (five times a week or more). If a person selected anything other than "never" on this instrument, helmet-wearing frequency was measured using a Likert scale ranging from 1 (never) to 6 (always).</p><p>Either an Abus (Phoenix, AZ) HS-10 S-Force peak bicycle helmet or a Beechfield (Bury, United Kingdom) B15 five-panel baseball cap was used to support the SensoMotoric (Teltow, Germany) head-mounted iView X HED-4.5 eye-tracking device (with its delicate 45° mirror removed; see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>). Participants responded to the scales using the Bristol Online Surveys Web site. All measures and the BART were completed on a 19-in. 4:3 LCD monitor. The experimenter "operated" an Applied Science Laboratories (Bedford, MA) Eye-Trac 6 desk-mounted optics system with Eye-Trac PC. A fake nine-point </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>eye-tracking calibration program was written in Real</head><p>Studio to increase the verisimilitude of the eye-tracking procedure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>This study was conducted in the University of Bath Department of Psychology's eye-tracking laboratory. Participants were brought into the laboratory and told that they would complete a number of computer-based risk-taking measures while their point of gaze was measured using a head-mounted eye tracker. After reading information about the study on the computer screen and agreeing to participate, they entered their age and gender and completed the STAI Y-1. A screen then appeared saying that the eye tracker would now be set up; the experimenter placed the cap-or helmet-mounted eye tracker on the participant's head, making a show of carefully aligning everything as in a real eye-tracking procedure. The experimenter then moved to the eye-tracking computer, where he or she ran the fake calibration software and conspicuously adjusted the eye-tracking controls to make it appear to participants that their eye movements were really being tracked. Participants then completed the Sensation-Seeking Scale, the BART, and the STAI Y-1 again. Afterward, a screen appeared saying that the eye tracker was to be turned off, and the experimenter removed the apparatus from participants' heads. Participants then completed the final STAI Y-1 before being debriefed, at which point they were informed of the deception and asked not to share details of the experiment with anyone else. They then reported their bicycling frequency and, if they did cycle, their helmet-wearing frequency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Wearing a helmet was associated with higher risk-taking scores (M = 40.40, SD = 18.18) than wearing a cap (M = 31.06, SD = 13.29), t(78) = 2.63, p = .01, d = 0.59 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2a</ref>). Similarly, participants who wore a helmet reported higher sensation-seeking scores (M = 23.23, SD = 7.00) than participants who wore a cap (M = 18.78, SD = 5.09), Welch's t(69.19) = 3.24, p = .002, d = 0.73 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2b</ref>). These effects cannot be explained by the helmet affecting anxiety, as anxiety did not change significantly as a function of condition, F(1, 78) = 0.19, p = .66, time of measurement, F(2, 156) = 2.37, p = .10, or an interaction between the two, F(2, 156) = 1.18, p = .31 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2c</ref>). Note that we used the square roots of the anxiety scores for analyses because of the skew seen in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2c</ref>. There was no relationship between risk taking and gender, t(78) = 0.45, p = .66, bicycling experience (ρ = .12, p = .27), and extent of helmet use when bicycling (ρ = .06, p = .60), nor, in regression modeling, interactions of any of these variables (e.g., the Condition × Bicycling Experience interaction was not significant; t = 0.39, p = .70). Prior research has shown that helmets do not affect cognitive performance in demanding laboratory tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bogerd, Walker, Brühwiler, &amp; Rossi, 2014)</ref>, which means the results cannot be attributed to this factor either.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Laboratory measures showed greater risk taking and sensation seeking when participants wore a helmet, rather than a baseball cap, during testing. These effects arose even though the helmet was introduced as a mount for an eye-tracking apparatus and not as safety equipment, and even though it could do nothing to alter participants' level of risk on the experimental task. Notably, the effect was an immediate shift in both risk taking and sensation seeking. This finding contrasts with those of previous work on unconscious influence, such as experiments on the persuasive effects of head movements <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Wells &amp; Petty, 1980)</ref> and environmental cues on consumer behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Berger &amp; Fitzsimons, 2008)</ref>, which looked instead at longer-term attitudinal changes from more overt signals.</p><p>Our findings are plausibly related to social priming, wherein social behaviors are cued by exposure to stereotypes or concepts <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bargh, 2006)</ref>. However, whereas social priming is generally understood in terms of behavior directed toward another person, the effects in this study were individual, focused on the risk-taking propensity of a person acting alone during exposure to a safety-related prime. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Schröder and Thagard (2013)</ref> produced computational models of social priming in which primes activate shared cultural concepts in people's minds, which in turn are associated with actions; through these links, the actions become available to the behavioral selection process. Speculatively, if what we saw in this study were to be understood through such mechanisms, with the helmet invoking concepts of protection from risk and thereby subconsciously shaping behaviors, our findings might suggest that Schröder and Thagard's social-priming framework operates even when its interaction target component (another person with whom to interact) is absent.</p><p>Our findings initially appear different from those of some other studies. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Fyhri and Phillips (2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Phillips et al., 2011)</ref> found that risk taking in downhill bicycling, measured through riding speed, did not simply increase when a helmet was worn; rather, the people who normally cycled with a helmet took fewer risks when riding without one. Why did the participants in Fyhri and Phillips's study who were not habitual helmet users not react to wearing a helmet with increased risk taking, as our experiment might suggest they would? Clearly more work is needed to definitively pin down all the mechanisms here, but for now, we speculate that the difference might be related to considerable variations between the two studies' procedures. Fyhri and Phillips greatly emphasized the physicality of their task ("to increase the difference in measures between the helmet-on and -off conditions, all participants were instructed to cycle using one-hand in both conditions"; p. 60), which provides a direct link between the action (bicycling) and the condition (helmet wearing) that was absent in our study. Moreover, that study used a repeated measures design, in which participants were aware they were riding a bicycle both with and without a helmet. This could have meant that behavior changed through mechanisms different from those seen here, where participants took part only in one condition and were not aware of any manipulation, nor even that they were specifically wearing a safety device.</p><p>The practical implication of our findings, in which risk taking changed in a global way when the helmet was worn, might be to suggest more extreme unintended consequences of safety equipment in hazardous situations than has previously been thought. The idea that people might take more risks when wearing safety equipment designed to protect against those risks has a considerable <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Adams, 1982</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Adams, , 1995;;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Adams &amp; Hillman, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hedlund, 2000)</ref>, although not uncontroversial <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(McKenna, 1988)</ref>, history. If this laboratory demonstration of globally increased risk taking arising from localized protection were to be replicated in real settings, this could suggest that people using protective equipment against specific hazards might also be unduly inclined to take risks that such protective equipment cannot reasonably be expected to guard against. This is not to suggest that the safety equipment will necessarily have its specific utility nullified, but rather that there could be changes in behavior wider than previously envisaged.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Photos showing how the eye tracker was mounted in each of the two conditions: to a baseball cap (left) and a bicycle helmet (right).</figDesc><graphic coords="2,61.52,470.81,479.95,214.03" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig.2. Distribution of scores for the helmet and cap conditions on (a) the Balloon Analogue Risk Task (BART), (b) the Sensation-Seeking Scale, and (c) state anxiety, measured using the State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI). For anxiety, scores are shown separately for time points before donning the eye tracker (Time 1), while wearing the eye tracker (Time 2), and after removing the eye tracker (Time 3). For each measure, the mean score across conditions is indicated by a vertical dotted line, and the mean score for each condition separately is indicated by a thick vertical line. Individual participants' scores are shown as thin vertical lines (rug points; stacked when more than 1 participant obtained the same score). Overlaid on the rug-point plots are kernel-density curves (with arbitrary scaling) that illustrate the overall distribution of scores within each condition.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors thank <rs type="person">A. Laketa</rs> and <rs type="person">R. Posner</rs> for their work in recruiting and testing participants.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author Contributions</head><p>T. Gamble and I. Walker developed and designed the study, analyzed and interpreted the data, and drafted the manuscript.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Declaration of Conflicting Interests</head><p>The authors declared that they had no conflicts of interest with respect to their authorship or the publication of this article.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Open Practices</head><p>All data have been made publicly available via Open Science Framework and can be accessed at <ref type="url" target="https://osf.io/eky4s/">https://osf.io/eky4s/</ref>. The complete Open Practices Disclosure for this article can be found at <ref type="url" target="http://pss.sagepub.com/content/by/supplemental-data">http://pss.sagepub.com/content/by/supplemental-data</ref>. This article has received a badge for Open Data. More information about the Open Practices badges can be found at <ref type="url" target="https://osf.io/tvyxz/wiki/1.%20View%20the%20Badges/">https://osf  .io/tvyxz/wiki/1.%20View%20the%20Badges/</ref> and <ref type="url" target="http://pss.sagepub.com/content/25/1/3.full">http://pss  .sagepub.com/content/25/1/3.full</ref>.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The efficacy of seat belt legislation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4271/820819</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Transactions of the Society of Automotive Engineers</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Warrendale, PA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Society of Automotive Engineers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1982">1982</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2824" to="2838" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Risk</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>London, England</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>UCL Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The risk compensation theory and bicycle helmets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1136/ip.7.2.89</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Injury Prevention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What have we been priming all these years? On the development, mechanisms, and ecology of nonconscious social behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bargh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/ejsp.336</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dogs on the street, pumas on your feet: How cues in the environment influence product evaluation and choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Fitzsimons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1509/jmkr.45.1</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of a helmet on cognitive performance is, at worst, marginal: A controlled laboratory study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bogerd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Brühwiler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.apergo.2013.09.009</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Ergonomics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="671" to="676" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional reactions to cycle helmet use</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fyhri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Phillips</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.aap.2012.03.027</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risky business: Safety regulations, risk compensation, and individual behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hedlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1136/ip.6.2.82</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Injury Prevention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Seat-belt wearing and driving behavior: An instrumented-vehicle study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Janssen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0001-4575(94)90095-7</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="249" to="261" />
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of a behavioral measure of risk taking: The Balloon Analogue Risk Task (BART)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lejuez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kahler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Richards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Ramsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stuart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/1076-898X.8.2.75</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task difficulty, risk, effort and comfort in a simulated driving task-implications for Risk Allostasis Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lewis-Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Rothengatter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.aap.2009.06.011</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1053" to="1063" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What role should the concept of risk play in theories of accident involvement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Mckenna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00140138808966692</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ergonomics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="469" to="484" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding children&apos;s injury-risk behavior: Wearing safety gear can lead to increased risk taking</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Morrongiello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Walpole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lassenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.aap.2006.10.006</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="618" to="623" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk compensation and bicycle helmets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Phillips</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fyhri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sagberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1539-6924.2011.01589.x</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Risk Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1187" to="1195" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An investigation of behavioural adaptation to airbags and antilock brakes among taxi drivers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sagberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fosser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Saetermo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0001-4575(96)00083-8</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="302" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The affective meanings of automatic social behaviors: Three mechanisms that explain priming</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schröder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Thagard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0030972</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="280" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Spielberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Manual for the State-Trait Inventory STAI (Form Y)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Palo Alto, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Mind Garden</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of overt head movements on persuasion: Compatibility and incompatibility of responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Petty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1207/s15324834basp0103_2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Basic and Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="219" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="1980">1980</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk homeostasis theory: An overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J S</forename><surname>Wilde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1136/ip.4.2.89</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Injury Prevention</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Xojo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Real Studio (Version 4.3)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Austin, TX</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Author</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Computer software</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sensation seeking in England and America: Cross-cultural, age, and sex comparisons</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zuckerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">B J</forename><surname>Eysenck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Eysenck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-006X.46.1.139</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="1978">1978</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
