<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Conspiracist Ideation as a Predictor of Climate-Science Rejection: An Alternative Analysis</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Ruth</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>
							<email>ruth.dixon@queens.ox.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Politics and International Relations</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Politics and International Relations</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oxford</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Manor Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>OX1 3UQ</postCode>
									<settlement>Oxford</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Conspiracist Ideation as a Predictor of Climate-Science Rejection: An Alternative Analysis</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">25BF01BF937825BF1BDBB31AC2F795CE</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797614566469pss.sagepub.</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received 9/12/14; Revision accepted 12/10/14</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.2" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-03T10:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<label type="revision">a91ee48</label>
					<label type="parameters">startPage=-1, endPage=-1, consolidateCitations=0, consolidateHeader=0, consolidateFunders=0, includeRawAffiliations=false, includeRawCitations=false, includeRawCopyrights=false, generateTeiIds=false, generateTeiCoordinates=[], sentenceSegmentation=false, flavor=null</label>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Commentary</head><p>Reanalysis of the survey data sets of <ref type="bibr">Lewandowsky, Oberauer, and Gignac (2013)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Lewandowsky, Gignac, and Oberauer (2013)</ref> indicates that the conclusions of those articles-that conspiracist ideation predicts skepticism regarding the reality of anthropogenic climate change-are not supported by the data. Nonlinear relationships were overlooked in both analyses, and this resulted in model misspecification. The authors used structural equation modeling (SEM) assuming linear relationships between the variables, and it is essential to test this assumption <ref type="bibr">(Bentler &amp; Chou, 1987, p. 86;</ref><ref type="bibr">Ullman, 2007, p. 683)</ref>. In this Commentary, we show, using nonparametric local regression, that this assumption does not hold for the relationship between conspiracist ideation and views on climate science, the relationship that produced one of the central claims of both articles and the majority of the press interest (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Corner, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Pearlman, 2012)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Data Sets and Variables</head><p>The invitation to one of the surveys <ref type="bibr">(Lewandowsky, Oberauer, &amp; Gignac, 2013)</ref> appeared on climate-related blogs from August through October 2010 (we refer to this as the blogs survey). In this survey, responses were on a 4-point scale from strongly disagree (1) to strongly agree (4); all 1,145 responses in the data set were analyzed. The second survey <ref type="bibr">(Lewandowsky, Gignac, &amp; Oberauer, 2013)</ref> involved U.S. citizens drawn from an Internet panel in June 2012 (we refer to this as the panel survey). In this survey, responses were on a 5-point scale from strongly disagree (1) to strongly agree (5), with a neutral option at the midpoint (3); all 1,001 responses in the data set were analyzed. The data sets are available through the publications page of Lewandowsky's Web site, <ref type="url" target="http://www.cogsciwa.com/">http://www  .cogsciwa.com/</ref>. We provide further details of the surveys and questions relating to the present analysis in Table <ref type="table">S1</ref> in the Supplemental Material available online.</p><p>We calculated composite variables for conspiracist ideation (CY) and endorsement of climate-change science (CLIM) for each data set by averaging the numerical responses to the relevant questions. Higher scores denoted higher levels of ideation or endorsement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis and Results</head><p>We initially analyzed the data from the blogs survey using ordinary least squares (OLS) fitting (see the left-hand plot in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">S1</ref> in the Supplemental Material). For the linear model predicting CLIM from CY, the coefficient of the linear term was -0.310, 95% confidence interval (CI) = <ref type="bibr">[-0.438, -0.182]</ref>. Although this coefficient was significantly negative, CY predicted less than 2% of the variance in CLIM (adjusted R 2 = .018). Furthermore, by far the largest group of respondents (41%) expressed maximum agreement with all five propositions relating to climate change (i.e., CLIM = 4.0), whereas only 15% were "more skeptical than not" (CLIM in the range of 1.0-2.4). This self-selected data set was therefore too skewed on the variable of interest to test the relationship properly. Figure <ref type="figure">S2</ref> in the Supplemental Material shows the distribution of cases for both variables in both data sets and clearly demonstrates the extreme skew of the blogs data set along CLIM (upper right-hand plot). <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Berk (1983)</ref> showed that nonrandom selection on an endogenous variable compromises both external and internal validity of a model (i.e., the results are not applicable even to the sample). We therefore turned to the population-sampled data set from the panel survey.</p><p>That sample was far less decided about climate change, having a median CLIM only slightly toward the "convinced" side. For the complete data set, simple linear regression (see the right-hand plot in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">S1</ref>) showed that CY marginally predicted CLIM, linear term = -0.062, 95% CI = [-0.118, -0.007], but accounted for much less than 1% of the variance (adjusted R 2 = .0039). However, there were 35 respondents who had responded "neutral" to all 11 questions relating to CLIM and CY. These respondents contributed to spikes at CY = 3 and CLIM = 3 (see the lower two panels of Fig. <ref type="figure">S2</ref> in the Supplemental Material). To test the effect of these satisficing respondents <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Krosnick, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kulas, Stachowski, &amp; Haynes, 2008)</ref> on the results, we performed a regression excluding their data (i.e., using data from the remaining 966 respondents). Excluding these cases resulted in the linear relationship between CY and CLIM becoming nonsignificant; the linear term was -0.056, 95% CI = [-0.113, 0.001]. This emphasizes the marginality of the original result.</p><p>Given the very weak nature of the linear relationship identified by OLS, we turned to the possibility of a nonlinear relationship between CY and CLIM, which we investigated using loess nonparametric local regression <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cleveland &amp; Devlin, 1988)</ref>. With nonlinear models, it is important to explore relationships in both directions, as nonlinear models cannot be easily transposed. In particular, a relationship that is nonmonotonic in one direction will be multivalued in the other, and loess fits are singlevalued functions. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> therefore shows loess fits for both CY predicting CLIM and CLIM predicting CY in the data from the panel survey. These plots were calculated using the R function loess (R Development Core Team, 2011) with default parameters (degree = 2, span = 0.75) and include estimated 95% CIs.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows that CY had very little predictive power for CLIM, but the fit in the transposed plot has an obvious bell-shaped curve. Respondents with high and low CLIM scores had very similar CY scores, and the highest conspiracist ideation was observed for respondents whose CLIM scores were neutral. It is therefore inappropriate to use a linear function of CY to predict CLIM, as the underlying relationship in that direction is multivalued.</p><p>Corresponding plots for the blogs-survey data are in the top row of Figure <ref type="figure">S3</ref> in the Supplemental Material. These plots are similar to Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> but less clear because of the extreme skew in the blogs data set. The middle row of Figure <ref type="figure">S3</ref> shows the effect of omitting from this data set the 18 cases with CY scores greater than 2.5, which was the sensitivity test that Lewandowsky et al. reported for the blogs survey. The original analysis of Lewandowsky et al. was robust to the removal of those cases, but we found that the nonparametric fits were substantially altered when those cases were removed, such that CY was no longer a significant predictor of CLIM, and the curvilinear relationship for CLIM as a predictor of CY became more prominent. (Plots of the panel-survey data set, as in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, are included in the bottom row of Fig. <ref type="figure">S3</ref> for comparison.) As implemented in both surveys, SEM does not produce meaningful results from multivalued functions (see <ref type="bibr">Bentler &amp; Chou, 1987, p. 86)</ref>.</p><p>Given the multivalued curved relationship, one might wonder why a linear correlation between CY and CLIM was seen in both data sets. It arose from an imbalance in responses along the CLIM scale in both cases: The preponderance of respondents on the right-hand side of the bell curve meant that this downward-sloping part of the curve prevailed in a linear fit, which led to an overall negative linear term in the OLS fit. This imbalance was subtle in the case of the panel survey, but very pronounced for the blogs survey, and consequently led to a more significant fit for that highly skewed data set and hence the misidentification of a linear term in the original SEM analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>This analysis highlights the fact that a skewed sample can easily mask a nonlinear relationship and lead to serious misinterpretation of modeled relationships <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Berk, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Groves, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">MacCallum &amp; Mar, 1995)</ref>. Techniques such as SEM should not be used as a "black box" without thorough initial exploration of the data set to check for nonlinearities <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bentler &amp; Chou, 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Cumming, 2014)</ref>. The curvilinear relationship identified in both the panelsurvey data of <ref type="bibr">Lewandowsky, Gignac, and Oberauer (2013)</ref> and the blogs-survey data of Oberauer, and Gignac (2013) suggests that both respondents convinced of anthropogenic climate change and respondents skeptical about such change were less likely to accept conspiracy theories than were those who were less decided about climate change.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig.1. Loess plots (with 95% confidence intervals) for the relationship between average conspiracist ideation (CY) and average endorsement of climate-change science (CLIM) in the data fromLewandowsky, Gignac, and  Oberauer (2013). Data points have been jittered(Chambers, Cleveland, Kleiner, &amp; Tukey, 1983, pp. 106-108).</figDesc><graphic coords="2,131.93,69.23,160.34,158.90" type="bitmap" /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author Contributions</head><p>The two authors contributed equally to the design and analysis of this study and to the writing of the manuscript.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Declaration of Conflicting Interests</head><p>The authors declared that they had no conflicts of interest with respect to their authorship or the publication of this article.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplemental Material</head><p>Additional supporting information can be found at <ref type="url" target="http://pss.sagepub.com/content/by/supplemental-data">http://pss  .sagepub.com/content/by/supplemental-data</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Open Practices</head><p>This Commentary is a reanalysis of data from two previous publications. The copyright to the data is held by the original authors, so we are unable to deposit the data in an open-access repository. At the time we submitted this manuscript, the data could be obtained from Web links provided by the original authors: The blogs data set was available at <ref type="url" target="http://websites.psychology.uwa.edu.au/labs/cogscience/Publications/LskyetalPsychSciClimate.xls">http://websites  .psychology.uwa.edu.au/labs/cogscience/Publications/  LskyetalPsychSciClimate.xls</ref>, and the panel data set was available at <ref type="url" target="http://websites.psychology.uwa.edu.au/labs/cogscience/documents/PLOSONE2013Data.csv">http://websites.psychology.uwa.edu.au/labs/cogscience/  documents/PLOSONE2013Data.csv</ref>. The complete Open Practices Disclosure for this article can be found at <ref type="url" target="http://pss.sagepub.com/content/by/supplemental-data">http://pss  .sagepub.com/content/by/supplemental-data</ref>.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical issues in structural modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bentler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-P</forename><surname>Chou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sociological Methods &amp; Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="78" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="1987">1987</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An introduction to sample selection bias in sociological data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Berk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Sociological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="386" to="398" />
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Graphical methods for data analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Cleveland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kleiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tukey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
			<publisher>Wadsworth &amp; Brooks</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Belmont, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Locally weighted regression: An approach to regression analysis by local fitting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Cleveland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="596" to="610" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Corner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.theguardian.com/environment/blog/2012/jul/27/climate-sceptics-conspiracy-theorists" />
		<title level="m">Are climate sceptics more likely to be conspiracy theorists? The Guardian</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-07-27">2012, July 27</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The new statistics: Why and how</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cumming</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonresponse rates and nonresponse bias in household surveys</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Groves</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Public Opinion Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="646" to="675" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Response strategies for coping with the cognitive demands of attitude measures in surveys</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Krosnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Middle response functioning in Likert-responses to personality items</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Kulas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Stachowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business and Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="259" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of conspiracist ideation and worldviews in predicting rejection of science</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gignac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0075637" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">75637</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NASA faked the moon landing-therefore, (climate) science is a hoax: An anatomy of the motivated rejection of science</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lewandowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Oberauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gignac</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="622" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing between moderator and quadratic effects in multiple regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Maccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="405" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pearlman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/earth/environment/climatechange/9503044/Climate-change-deniers-are-either-extreme-free-marketeers-or-conspiracy-theorists.html" />
		<title level="m">Climate change deniers &apos;are either extreme free marketeers or conspiracy theorists</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-08-28">2012, August 28</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Telegraph</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing</title>
		<author>
			<orgName type="collaboration">R Development Core Team</orgName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.R-project.org/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural equation modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Ullman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Using multivariate statistics</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Tabachnick</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fidell</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Pearson</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="676" to="780" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>5th international ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
